Brier S. Gallihugh, M.S.

989-423-6118 | Email: gallihughou@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Lancaster, OH 43130

SUMMARY

I am an experienced social psychology doctoral candidate and researcher specializing in work regarding prejudice and discrimination. I bring +7 years of experience in data science (including experimental design) and +2 years of psychometric experience resulting in +15 studies and 8 presentations across national and regional conferences. I am seeking to use my data science expertise to provide data driven insights and help advance organizational goals and objectives.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Proficient Language & Library Skills**: R | Tidyverse | ggplot2
- Basic Language & Library Skills: SQL | Python
- **Technical Writing:** Rmarkdown | Quarto
- **Software**: Git & GitHub | SPSS
- Statistical Modeling: Regression | Correlation | T-Test | ANOVA | Mediation & Moderation | SEM | Meta-Analysis
- Psychometrics: Scale Construction | Scale Development | Scale Validation | EFA | CFA
- Other: Dynamic Computational Modeling | Data Cleaning | Research Design | Data Analysis | Experimental Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Quantitative Researcher, Ohio University | Athens, OH

August 2020 - Present

- Designed, cleaned, analyzed, and created visualizations for +10 research studies using R to gain insight into human behavior and attitudes as a doctoral level student.
- Applied regression analyses, ANOVA and moderation analyses to investigate human behavior and intervention effectiveness.
- Disseminated analytical insights at regional and national science conferences in the form of 3 presentations and 3 talks at departmental colloquiums and regional psychological science conferences in addition to one registered report.

Junior Quantitative Researcher, Eastern Michigan University | Ypsilanti, MI

August 2017 – August 2021

- Designed, cleaned, analyzed, and created visualizations for 5 research studies using R to gain insight into human behavior and attitudes as a masters level student.
- Applied regression analyses, ANOVA and psychometrics to investigate human behavior, evaluate intervention effectiveness and construct and investigate the validity and reliability of a new psychological measure.
- Disseminated analytical insights at regional and national science conferences in the form of 2 presentations.

SELECTED PROJECTS

Black Lives Matter Support (BLM)

August 2020 - Present

Designed, implemented and analyzed behavioral data across 5 studies investigating predictors of support for the BLM
movement. Regression analysis suggested high multiculturalism and low assimilation beliefs positively predict support. A
link to the source code repository can be found HERE

Christian Privilege Scale

August 2018 - August 2021

Designed, implemented and analyzed a scale development project to create a valid measure of Christian privilege awareness
among Christian samples. Initial factor analysis and correlation analysis suggest the scale captures the intended privilege
metric. A link to the source code repository can be found <u>HERE</u>

PUBLICATIONS AND OTHER MEDIA

Gallihugh, B. & Rios, K. (2023). Inter-ethnic ideologies as predictors of black lives and all lives matter. In Preparation

Mackey, C. D., **Gallihugh, B.**, Rios, K., & Gervais, W. M. (2023). Faithless found: Replication and extension of Gervais (2011). *The International Journal for the Psychology of Religion*. Accepted In Principle (as a registered report)

Gallihugh, B. (2023). Statistical Analyses in R: A Two Day Crash Course. Hybrid Workshop at Ohio University. Materials can be found <u>HERE</u>

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Experimental Psychology Ohio University (Athens, OH)

August 2020 - Present

Master of Science (M.S.) in General Experimental Psychology Eastern Michigan University (Ypsilanti, MI) August 2017 - August 2021

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Psychology

August 2012 - May 2017

Saginaw Valley State University (Saginaw, MI)